-==http://www.1000fr.com==-
謦靈風軟影視論壇榮譽出品
本字幕僅供學習交流，嚴禁用於商業用途
-=風軟FRM字幕組=-
翻譯:HEBE 慳吝鬼
校對:慳吝鬼
我從沒讀過這樣的劇本...
但是其中主要人物之間的關係...
得到了觀眾的認可
這點我很認可
What do you
think of her, Han?
I'm trying not to, kid.
Good.
劇本包羅萬象
既有幽默 也不失真誠
Still, she's got a lot of spirit.
堶惘陵盜 有巫師
有農場男孩還有公主
And we had bickering robots,
and I thought, ''What's not to like?''
這種通俗的?述方式讓你可以...
進入人物的世界並享受這故事
星球大戰的人物
它變成了一種文化現象
它的主題 語句...
May the Force be with you.
和人物在全球數百萬人心中...
刻下了烙印
儘管星球大戰的宇宙似乎在...
George Lucas靈光一閃中形成...
它事實上與電影大相徑庭
故事原先是關於Luke Starkiller
Starkiller在根本上是父親...
雙胞胎是他的孩子
最終發展為雙胞胎之一...
與反派父親的故事
我寫了很多草稿
把故事翻來覆去...
設法找到合適的一種
儘管他們把故事設置在遙遠的星系...
星球大戰的人物包含了
神話傳說中的經典原型
For luck.
Lucas花了兩年多的時間寫劇本...
仔細拼湊各部分
寫劇本的時候
常常要移動人物
就像一套棋子
有主要角色...
有次要角色 有同夥...
有壞人還有黨羽
你要移動他們
想辦法把故事編好
為了讓紙上的人物變成三維活物...
Lucas雇傭了插畫家Ralph McQuarrie.
在創作科幻與奇幻故事時...
與一位插畫家工作十分有益...
使大腦堛漯F西形象化...
這樣我就不用花大量時間...
描述所有的小細節
只要畫一張畫就行了
我與Ralph一同坐下...
我告訴他人物是什麼
長什麼樣子...
讓後他會畫一系列草圖
我看過草圖跟他說
''不 我要這樣 我要那樣
眼睛要大一點
我要他小點''
有時候會完全不同
電影堻怚j老的原型人物...
就是星球大戰的英雄
Luke Skywalker
神話故事中沒有任何特定人物...
直接與Luke Skywalker有聯繫
Luke Skywalker是一個英雄
他更像是眾多...
傳說與童話書中的普遍典型
例如Joseph Campbell寫的『千面英雄』
Luke Skywalke是個狠角色...
因為那一類型角色的天性...
他們得是普通人
他們得讓我們觀眾產生同感
He was the person
that we went on this journey with.
Luke Skywalker的有力造型...
註定能捕捉到一代影迷的想像...
要是他由Kenny Baker扮演
還會那麼受歡迎嗎?
我本把Luke Skywalker寫成一個侏儒...
農場堛漫狾酗H
the aunt and the uncle
那一群人
都是小矮人
That boy is our last hope.
No, there is another.
雙胞胎和他們父親的故事
這自始至終都沒改動
有一次 我讓雙胞胎中的女孩當英雄...
最終 我把它改成男性人物
- I'm not going anywhere.
- They're gonna execute her.
You said you didn't want to just wait
to be captured. Now you want to stay?
Marching into the detention area
is not what I had in mind.
- But they're gonna kill her.
- Better her than me.
講述故事的方法之一就是
設置兩個主要人物...
他們與對方完全相反
這樣可以形成對比
Luke是一個理想主義的
天真農場男孩...
他即將走向世界
心中有一點慌亂
要承擔責任
堶惘陪茠曭
一個嚮導和教育者...
帶他啟程 給與忠告
You must learn the ways of the Force
if you're to come with me to Alderaan.
Alderaan?
通常還要設置一個同夥...
他的道德觀等方面都與英雄相反
他們經常會意見不合
在這部電影中...
主題之一是同情與互助
無私對自私
一個人物十分無私...
I'm Luke Skywalker.
I'm here to rescue you.
另一個人物十分自私
I ain't in this for your revolution,
and I'm not in it for you, Princess.
I expect to be well paid.
I'm in it for the money.
我把他們放在一起
所以他們遇到情況時...
總會意見分歧
Han Solo是我們都希望能成為的人物
我認為大多數人
都覺得自己像Luke Skywalker...
但是我們都情願當Han Solo
Lucas起先把Han Solo構想成...
一個巨大的綠皮怪物
長著大鰓
被Wookiees養大
Solo在早年與Chewbacca交了朋友...
他們在一起成為了星際海盜
Han Solo本來是一個窮兇極惡的人物
他本來是一個怪物
或是古怪的外星人
我最終決定他是人類...
這樣他們三人間就能有更多關係
這就是Chewbacca是外星同夥的緣由
星球大戰的幾個人物
來源於神化傳說...
Han Solo的同夥Chewbacca...
是受到了個人關係的啟發
Chewbacca的原始靈感來自我的狗 Indiana
我寫劇本的時候
她一直坐在我身邊
她坐在我車
當我的副駕駛員
她坐在車堛漁伬堋穨琱@樣高
她是阿拉斯加愛斯基摩狗
她非常大
我覺得那情景很有趣
當我想為Han Solo找外星副駕駛員時...
我立馬就想到了Indiana.
有一張30年代的圖片...
毛茸茸像猿的動物 George很喜歡
我說道 ''把他的臉畫的更像松鼠或貓''
我們想畫某一屬動物的特徵...
而不是某一個特定的動物品種
一開始 我們把他畫得像狐猴
之後 我畫了一個下面長了乳房的生物
我去除了乳房
因為它不是女性
我加上了子彈帶
給了他武器
電影製作的每一方面...
幾乎都是協力完成的
星球大戰的人物創作也是如此
我腦中產生一個主意...
我要某個人物 外星人 或者場景是什麼樣子
然後 我會告訴設計師我的想法...
讓他畫下來 使之形象化
- I got him!
- Great, kid. Don't get cocky.
接著 我要把畫稿交給美術部門...
或是道具部門 或是化妝部門...
他們會把它轉化成...
真實的 機械的 塑膠的或毛制的實體
在那時候 我們並沒有能力做動畫...
所以我決定 Chewbacca將由...
一個高大的人穿著外套表演
他們說那東西毛多個大 就這麼多
我們到了那 參觀了一下...
Ralph McQuarrie站在那
拿著一張尼安德塔人的圖畫
區別在於Ralph讓Chewie穿上了...
百慕大短褲和背心
I had no choice.
What are you doing?
Trust him!
為了讓Chewbacca的面部表情可信...
Lucas求助於行業中少數的專家之一
我與Stuart Freeborn合作
他在(太空奧德賽)2001婸s作了猿人
我認為他的作品很棒
而且 既然我們有Wookiee...
我說道 ''我們要用2001堛漪萓P技術製作猿人''
356 第四次
他把Ralph的畫稍作改動...
並讓Peter Mayhew扮演
他的身體結構
他的行走方式
他的眼睛
測量他的實際骨架結構
去製作戲服...
和能機械運動的臉
改變了設計
現實情況改變了設計
當你有個設計思路
想把它投入現實...
大多數時候
特別是在早期...
一切都會改動
現在 有了數位技術
構思了某個東西...
設計了某個東西
讓其原汁原味地出來就容易多了
但是在從前
沒有這回事
We seem to be made to suffer.
It's our lot in life.
給了我星球大戰開頭靈感的電影之一...
是黑澤明的『戰國英豪』
講的是兩個處於封建日本社會底層的農民
Matashichi, this is hell.
It's the end!
If we're going to die,
let's die together.
與將軍和公主同行
貴族階級的人
Just prepare the rice.
Shut up. I can't take it anymore.
You can stuff your orders.
故事是從他們的角度講述的
I'm not one of them.
從最低的社會階層來看這場冒險...
這場發生在最宏大的國際外交層面上的冒險
他們被設計成一種Mutt and Jeff...
- Don't kick the stones.
- You stop grabbing my leg.
Abbott and Costello Laurel and Hardy
對電影的戲劇性調劑
I've just about had enough of you.
Go that way.
You'll be malfunctioning within a day,
you nearsighted scrap pile.
And don't let me catch you
following me, begging for help...
because you won't get it.
要喜劇性調劑有效果
你得創造兩個迥然不同的人物...
我設置了一個小astrodroid...
與人類沒有任何相似之處...
另一個是更高雅的翻譯droid...
它被賦予人形...
被編程 使之能更好地與人類交流
I am C-3PO,
human-cyborg relations.
This is my counterpart, R2-D2.
Hello.
我要為3PO找一個非常高雅複雜的設計構思...
因為3PO來自于一個更高雅複雜的環境
I'm not much more than an interpreter
and not very good at telling stories.
3PO的早期構思
受到了『大都會』中機器人的啟發
3PO要看起來像『大都會』中的機器人
不過是個男子...
我畫了一幅
3PO和R2穿越沙漠的畫...
你可以在其背景看到他們的太空艙
創造3PO最困難的事情之一...
就是得做一個完全中性的臉...
這樣我才能讓它讀入不同情景中...
表達的各種情緒
我雇了一個女雕刻家
她做了一系列頭像...
設法做一個完全中性的頭像...
上面完全沒有任何情緒
我要它所有的反應...
都來源於它周圍的環境和情節...
如果他開心
你就能從他的臉上讀出喜悅
如果他傷心
你就能從他的臉上讀出悲傷
完全不被他的臉部構造所歪曲
Don't call me a mindless philosopher,
you overweight glob of grease.
Come out,
before somebody sees you.
我本來要他像個...
油嘴滑舌的二手車經銷商或推銷員
他要更像個推銷員
總是想討好別人
總是說大道理
-Can you speak Bocce?
-Of course. It's like a second language.
-All right. Shut up. I'll take this one.
-Shutting up, sir.
當Tony Daniels來了之後
他是個好演員
他操著英國口音
我愛上了那口音
我試過很多不同的人
我試過二手汽車經銷商
我試過推銷員
無一奏效 除了Tony他那種煩人的英國管家
到星球大戰攝影棚的第一天...
他們才剛好完成戲服...
我穿上之後...
我對場記員說
''請你拿塊偏光板來...
把它舉高''
通過那小眼睛
And through the little eyes, I looked
at a little Polaroid of myself...
and that's where I really learned
totally what I looked like for the day.
If I told you half the things
I've heard about this Jabba the Hutt...
you'd probably
short-circuit.
我們首先見到3PO時
他通體金黃
攝影棚娷\亮閃閃的東西很危險...
因為它會反射所有東西
從外面開著的補給車...
到端茶小姐 到護士
而且 George的世界充滿了
糞料 骨頭和塵土...
所以3PO滿身污泥
完全違背他的本性 當然
This oil bath is going to feel so good.
I've got such a bad case of dust
contamination I can barely move.
他總是在結尾時被擦亮
這在星球大戰中...
是一種演出結束 大步行走之裝
總是被擦得亮閃閃的
3PO有趣的一點是
他沒有靈魂
他被編程要以特定方式思考
並富有同情心...
但他並不知道那是什麼意思
Chewie, take the professor in the back
and plug him into the hyperdrive.
Sometimes I just don't
understand human behavior.
有時候他會很沮喪
有許多類人品質...
但是他沒有可獨自思考的主要部位
Darth Vader 另一方面
他變得越來越機械化...
他喪失越來越多的能力
甚至不能像人一樣思考
起先 有好父親和壞父親
好父親是Anakin Starkiller
壞父親是Darth Vader
在寫劇本的時候
那兩個人物稍微變換了位置
我思來想去
最終他們合併成了一個人物
Obi-Wan never told you
what happened to your father.
He told me enough.
He told me you killed him.
I am your father.
將古代傳說中好壞父親合併的決定...
創造了一個難以忘懷的人物...
由於他處於人和機器之間的本性
此人物得到了提升
Darth Vader棄人從機器...
他不斷喪失自己的靈魂
喪失自己的人性...
這是主題
Darth Vader這人物
Lucas的最初設計構思...
來自于阿拉伯半島的貝都因武士
George進來向我描述Darth Vader...
一個迎著風 飄忽不定的輪廓
十分黑暗 幽靈般的人物
他可能戴著一個大頭盔
就像中古時期的日本武士
McQuarrie很快意識到星際旅行...
會影響到他的人物設計
他的解決方案成了Darth Vader最險惡的特點之一
他要從一個太空船而來...
在走道中炸開一個洞...
從而進入另一個太空船
我開始為他擔心...
不穿太空服而穿過真空太空
George不太情願地說道...
''那就去給他加上呼吸面罩''
我每做一件事
做到一定程度 他就會說...
''好了 就這樣
我們繼續去做其他事'
Darth Vader就此了結...
電影堛漸L與我畫的差不多
George Lucas的成就
與托爾金一樣
他創造了值得紀念的人物
You've taken
your first step into a larger world.
我認為他碰觸到了
非常有力和根本的東西
I'm not afraid.
You will be.
今日想起星球大戰
電影最初播放的25年後...
你會記不起那些特技
但是你記得那些人物
Darth Vader和Han Solo...
和Yoda和Luke Skywalker還有Chewbacca.
人物留了下來
Why, you stuck-up, half-witted...
scruffy-looking nerf herder!
Who's scruffy-lookin'?
平心而論 你要從George...
對於人性和電影理解的才華講起
There's nothing for me here now.
I want to learn the ways of the Force
and become a Jedi like my father.
這些神話經受了時間的考驗...
被觀眾們所喜愛
因為其中的人物
在構思和扮演上都非常美妙
Great shot, kid!
That was one in a million!
Remember, the Force
will be with you always.
Han, can you reach my lightsaber?
Can anyone?
That's my face.
I thought that was
a deer's ass in here.
Cut!
Cheer them on, guys.
Cheer them on.
Try and climb up,
get back down again.
Beat the-- out of them!
And cut.
他是你最愛的壞人
他是個切實的反派角色
它要麼讓你害怕 要麼讓你激動
I find your lack of faith disturbing.
那呼吸聲讓人膽寒
第三部在根本上講的是...
Anakin Skywalker如何變成了Darth Vader...
我認為大家都在等待這故事
這是Anakin終結的開頭
You don't know the power
of the dark side.
the return of
Darth Vader
我回過頭來拍前傳講述...
Anakin Skywalker如何變成了Darth Vader
是因為這故事很有趣 很有娛樂性...
是因為它講述了
一個好人變壞的歷程
他從一個伶俐聰明...
富有愛心和同情心的小男孩...
發展成一個細心 刻苦...
但野心勃勃的Padawan learner...
他覺得因為自己who feels that
because he's better at being a Jedi...
and his Jedi skills
than most of the otherJedi...
所以應該進步得更深更快
In some ways--
a lot of ways--
I'm really ahead of him.
等他進步了 他無法控制自己的脾氣...
他想控制事物的貪欲
這使他走向了毀滅
他陷入原力黑暗面經過了周密安排...
源自於十分具有人性的事情
他陷入愛河
他即將成為一個父親...
他嫉妒了
我不清楚
我們把事情混成一團...
因為我們都年輕天真
無法退一步...
然後說 ''哦 不 沒關係的''
Put the ship down!
Don't let your personal feelings
get in the way!
Anakin從始到終的問題就是...
他不願意放手
I don't want things to change.
But you can't stop the change.
當他不斷尋求更多力量
去改變人們的命運...
讓那些人按他的意思過
試圖拯救所愛之人的貪欲...
變成了控制宇宙的能力
第三部現在缺少一部分...
那是第三部關鍵的一部分
也是大家一直想看到的...
就是Anakin Skywalker穿上suit的回歸
面部 構思...
Ralph McQuarrie早前的靈感還在...
我們試圖忠於原作
看到原始頭盔後...
我們發現它的形狀不對稱
我們有機會把它做得更對稱...
這就是我們要做的
所有細節都在這板上...
所以我們花了很多時間
把這一側弄漂亮
我把它掃描進機器
我在電腦塈漭汕蝴L來...
我現在正在切割右邊臉
今天結束前 我們有望把兩半合起來
看看效果
那將是人們第一次見到對稱的Darth Vader
我們開始做頭盔了
明天要注模
肩膀做好了
頭部也在做了
幾個星期後 這些部分將被拼成Darth Vader
這樣很好
但我們還要做boxes
我們要開始做fittings
起初 是一件米色的suit...
看上去一點都不嚇人
但是一種懷舊之情湧上心頭...
我不曉得即將會有什麼感覺
I've been waiting for you, Obi-Wan.
We meet again at last.
他們本可以
隨便找個高個子就混過去...
不過我又求又請
他們也十分好心地...
給我量身定做了一套Darth Vader suit
把頭盔罩上...
堶惇搕W去太瘦了
我不曉得你能不能看清楚
在這邊加上一個小管子...
再加一塊輔料
整個輪廓就出來了 也把臉填滿了
也更像我們記憶中的形象
這種事情很怪
我們總是在發現
那些我們以為已經會了的東西
同時
我們要做一個...
Anakin和Obi-Wan兩人
互相鬥劍的場景
這是個十分困難的事情
這(兩人)是好朋友
你知道 這是他的良師益友...
他們的友誼破碎了
Anakin就讓它發生了
Obi-Wan似乎總是對那小孩心存戒心...
向他奄奄一息的師父Qui-Gon做了保證...
他保證要把小孩訓練成Jedi
並照顧他...
他做到了 我認為
盡他所能
在鬥劍中
你要學上千種招數
這很困難 你還得記住它們
你必須得牢牢記住
不然頭就會挨劈
手指頭?
每個場景都要重複打很多遍...
要做得盡可能完美...
十分累人
我們要重做一遍
很辛苦 不過一天結束時
我們倆都會很滿足
那些傢伙十分投入...
一個人犯了錯誤
boom-暫停
他們都沒事
有說有笑
boom-過幾秒鐘
他們又練起來了
他們每天都能持續好幾個小時
Ewan一直都是個好劍客...
不過Hayden富有運動細胞
他打得也很好
這一場的特別之處在於
他們要對打
所以他們都很賣力...
每天都把常規做完
努力超過對方
And that leads into this.
They've done more layers
of the silicone...
and then we've done
a fiberglass jacket around it.
We've then taken all of that off
so we could get the original shape out.
So we now have an empty shell, which
is going to be our Darth Vader helmet...
which now Adam is about to start
laying up in polyester--in fiberglass.
新鮮出爐 Darth Vader頭盔
看起來蠻不賴的
我認為Hayden一定會很激動
扮演Darth Vader
進入Darth Vader
這是最酷的部分
給Hayden再試穿一次
拍到電影上
接著它就成為回憶了
我們組所有人
都想參與制作這個
我們跟他去攝影棚的那天
他走進鏡頭...
你看著他閃閃發光...
想到 ''這真是件神奇的事情''
帶我們回到了過去
很久很久以前
在一個遙遠的星系
星球大戰傳奇的下一篇章
絕地歸來
善與惡的戰鬥愈演愈烈
加入這一群人的冒險...
Luke Skywalker...
Han Solo...
Leia公主...
Lando Calrissian...
Chewbacca...
C-3PO和R2-D2...
還有Darth Vader
一次去外星世界的旅程
It's a trap.
一場對壓迫的反抗鬥爭
一部英雄與惡棍的史詩
一場同宇宙一樣大的冒險
絕地歸來
將在你星系的指定影院上映
鐳射劍的誕生
40年代的海盜電影和浪漫主義電影
絕對影響了星球大戰
『羅賓漢歷險記』(1938)
Errol Flynn演的那種電影
在那一段時間 電影院堨是...
奇幻 動作冒險流派的電影
For luck.
星球大戰的前提是
它為一部浪漫主義奇幻電影...
富有神話中的浪漫主義傳統...
你知道的 『亞瑟王』
打鬥的浪漫一面...
富有騎士精神和榮耀之類的
為了發揚一群和平衛士...
他們高於一切
受人尊敬 有決定權...
為星系帶來和平...
我需要能和絕地相稱的武器
Your father wanted you to have this
when you were old enough...
but your uncle wouldn't allow it.
- What is it?
- Your father's lightsaber.
This is the weapon of a Jedi knight.
Not as clumsy or random
as a blaster.
An elegant weapon...
for a more civilized age.
它更像是一段簡約時期的象徵...
那時候帝國尚未掌權
而是由榮耀來統治
電影中 它不只是一種實際武器
更是一種象徵
Hokey religions and ancient weapons
are no match for a blaster at your side.
You don't believe
in the Force, do you?
原始構思是絕地用劍打鬥
之後 我想換成更有未來主義的劍...
所以我把它換成了鐳射劍...
給了它一種科技優勢
在那射線槍橫流的時代...
它可以偏轉射線
既然前提是絕地用它們防身...
不是用來進攻 而是防禦...
在射線槍世界堨恓J射劍...
作為防禦武器再適合不過
It started out as a kind of
Oriental form of swordplay...
where there was a lot of honor involved
and a lot of skill and craft...
and higher spiritual meaning
to the sword fight.
So they were very simple.
In the beginning...
the first film, Episode IV...
it was a fight between
a very old man...
and a man who was only partially
a man and mostly a mechanical being.
So it wasn't really
much of a sword fight at all.
When I left, I was but a learner.
Now I am the master.
Only a master of evil, Darth.
鐳射劍最初是
四乘五相機的閃光附件
我們把圓形的閃光部分拆下來
用它來做鐳射劍
George堅持說那些劍...
十分 十分重
重到不能單手拿
我們一直得用兩隻手
就像一把Excalibur
有40,50磅重
非常的強大
堶採郁t了大量能量
揮動它們的時候
感覺很沉重...
因為它們撞到一起的時候...
會產生巨大的爆炸 等等等等
到後來...
我們讓鐳射劍鬥
變得更快更激烈...
因為Luke的劍藝越來越高
所以 我們慢慢把東方式的雙手持劍...
變為不時用單手持劍
繼續發展下去...
成了雙手和單手混用
不過起先
你必須用兩隻手拿鐳射劍...
因為要揮動大量的能量
You see? You can do it.
I call it luck.
In my experience,
there's no such thing as luck.
鐳射劍的效果
基本上是根旋轉的棒子...
上面塗了銀幕材料...
這樣它就能以多倍亮度...
把光源反射回去
問題是 如果你把它移出一定範圍...
它就不再反光...
變回了旋轉的棒子
我們在表面纏上反光膠帶
這樣它就能發光照亮演員
這方法沒奏效
他們會打壞鐳射劍
之後 我們採用了塗反光材料的棍子
再後來 我們更加...
精通於製作鬥劍
我們採用了無反光材料的劍...
我們決定不再通過鏡頭拍攝光...
和很多其他的過程...
這樣我們拍攝打鬥時可以輕鬆些
118BT 第二鏡 A相機
And action!
我原以為他們以後
會把卡通劍身放進去
不過 如果你在鬥劍...
你就不會停手
你需要找東西來敲
每一把鐳射劍都是半真半畫的
我們需要真的棒子
來告訴我們劍身的位置
有時候我們會用短劍身
因為他們要近戰...
會打到場景堛漯F西
有時候我們不用劍身...
因為劍會在鏡頭中展開...
或者他們的動作太過複雜...
無法用劍來模擬
我們之後會把劍加進去
但這需要很仔細地追蹤軌跡...
計算出劍身的位置
再後來 到了第二第三部(V VI)...
他們認為當場拍攝得不償失...
全部在後期完成
我們仍然用一小段棒子...
這樣就有個東西可以打
這多虧于特技的進步...
而不是其他方面
我們的轉描技術越來越僂...
早期畫面-轉描之前
未重合的轉描
我們用了更先進的技術...
更近的轉描 仍然未重合
來更容易地跟蹤那些劍...
複製下來
製作鐳射劍
最終畫面
You are beaten.
It is useless to resist.
Don't let yourself be destroyed
as Obi-Wan did.
儘管在拍攝的時候
鐳射劍看上去有些蹩腳...
在後期製作時
他們給其上了應有的樣子
當然還有
Ben Burtt出色的聲音效果
第一部電影中鐳射劍的聲效
被交給了Ben Burtt
Ben從一開頭...
我寫劇本的時候就開工了
我告訴他我需要R2的聲音
我需要Darth Vader呼吸的聲音
我需要射線槍的聲音
我需要鐳射劍的聲音
我為這電影製作的
第一個聲效是鐳射劍
我記得在當時
我在牆上看了Ralph McQuarrie的一些作品
畫的是Luke在電影結尾鬥劍
他們拿著鐳射劍
我立馬就想到了
我覺得我知道它們會發什麼聲音
在電影放映室
那些放映機會發出嗡嗡聲
他們不在運轉 只是閒置著
馬達在那邊發著...
一種魔幻神秘的嗡鳴聲...
某方面來說 我覺得很悅耳
我想道 ''這大概就是鐳射劍的聲音''
Your powers are weak, old man.
You can't win, Darth.
If you strike me down...
I shall become more powerful
than you can possibly imagine.
我當時還找了些其他元素
我有一台答錄機
話筒線壞了
包裹物脫落了
我在公寓婺g過電視機的時候...
顯像管堛熄隞嬼n
通過破線傳了出來
產生蜂鳴 我說道
''這蜂鳴好聽 聽上去很危險''
我把蜂鳴聲錄了下來
健全的人通常不會要嗡鳴聲
這一次 嗡鳴聲就是答案
當然 我要錄入聲音...
把劍掠過發出的嗖嗖聲去掉
他花了大半年時間製作那些聲音
我首次加入鐳射劍的聲效的地方
是在一段電影的臨時剪輯
對它沒有多少評論
但我從此明白
沒有評論 那就是很棒
那就是通過測試
Impressive.
Most impressive.
最終 鐳射劍的聲音...
因為我們要富有能量的感覺...
是幾種不同聲音的組合
從嘩嘩響的真空吸塵器...
到一種擊打乾冰的碰撞聲
那之後我們做了改進
因為武器移動得更快了...
最新電影中我們有雙頭鐳射劍
但都是基於相同的錄音
There's nothing you could have done,
had you been there.
You'd have been killed too...
and the droids would now be
in the hands of the Empire.
I want to come with you to Alderaan.
There's nothing for me here now.
I want to learn the ways of the Force
and become a Jedi like my father.
在每一部中 從 IV V和VI...
我不斷改善劍鬥...
因為我假設Luke正成為...
更強的劍客
他在學更多的東西
但與此同時...
他並沒有按Jedi傳統的方式進行訓練
AJedi uses the Force
for knowledge and defense...
never for attack.
- But tell me why I can't--
- No. There is no why.
Nothing more
will I teach you today.
在Empire Strikes Back中...
反派人物和正派人物首次交手
所以 這是場大仗...
Luke已經足夠精通...
可以與Darth Vader交手
所以 這是場稍微一邊倒的劍鬥...
Vader稍勝一籌
在這場打鬥戲中...
Luke並不知道Vader是他父親
他以為自己在打仇敵
所以他盡全力地去打
他以為自己在打殺父仇人...
打殺死Obi-Wan Kenobi的人...
打宇宙中邪惡附身的人
在下一場打鬥中...
兩人不分伯仲
再下一場
Return of the Jedi...
他知道自己在與父親對打
I see you have constructed
a new lightsaber.
他知道皇帝是幕後黑手
Your skills are complete.
他也知道他在處理的問題...
比劍鬥大得多
Indeed you are powerful,
as the emperor has foreseen.
所以這場劍鬥更注重
于劍鬥時的感情背景...
而不是劍鬥本身
Never!
這是電影的高潮
而不是高科技戰爭 死星爆炸之類的...
這是更個人的劍鬥
父子之間的較量
然後我們拍攝了前傳...
其中Jedi in their full flower...
按過去的方式鬥劍
訓練有素的絕地
我們要把他們的劍鬥動作做得更快...
更複雜 更有攻擊性
我們延續了下去
Brave of you, boy.
But I would have thought
you had learned your lesson.
I am a slow learner.
Anakin!
比起第IV V和VI
劍鬥變得更加殘忍
Fought well you have,
my old Padawan.
This is just the beginning.
一個基於一個
因為劍鬥變得更加私人...
直到第三部
這是一場非常私人的較量
這一場 他們要殊死搏鬥
所以時間很長
現場 "Star Wars Episode III"
兩個人物間的區別是
Obi-Wan經驗更豐富...
但Anakin更強大
很不錯
Thanks, everybody.
You know, I'm here today
as Luke Skywalker...
but I'm also here
to talk about Sprint.
As you can see, you stand to save
up to 1 7 cents a month...
over the more
dependable providers.
Luke Skywalker與Han Solo
救出了公主...
摧毀了死星
但他們的故事還沒結束
有史以來最火電影的製作者們...
帶給你星球大戰傳奇的下一部
帝國反擊戰
我們英雄的故事延續...
Luke Skywalker...
Princess Leia...
Han Solo...
C-3PO...
R2-D2...
和Chewbacca.
並介紹Lando Calrissian
這部史詩包含了浪漫...
包含了英雄和惡棍
他們穿過杳無人跡的真空
來到了未知的世界
對抗壓迫的銀河奧德賽
星球大戰傳奇的新冒險
帝國反擊戰
明年夏天在你的星系上映
I'm Luke Skywalker.
I'm here to rescue you.
它是有史以來最受歡迎的太空冒險
''Exciting''is hardly
the word I would choose.
它是好萊塢歷史上最先鋒的傳奇之一
There'll be no one
to stop us this time.
它以一種不可抗力捕獲了想像力...
You've taken your first step
into a larger world.
並把三名年輕演員變成了超級明星
- I got him!
- Great kid! Don't get cocky.
星球大戰獲得成功後
紛紛而來的機會...
改變了我的整個人生
它是一則奇妙的寓言
I'll never turn to the dark side.
It's Geroge's vision
and he truly is a visual man
in a profound way.
但是星球大戰三部曲...
不止改變了我們視電影的方式
它改變了電影拍攝的方式
You must unlearn
what you have learned.
George造就了許多東西...
其改變了我們所知的(電影)行業
We did it!
一則星系童話的成功...
超越了任何人最狂野的夢想
The Force will be with you always.
我本打算永遠都不去拍熱門電影
這不是我的安排
我並沒期望星球大戰會如此熱門
但它成為了一種現象
=夢想的帝國=
星球大戰三部曲的故事
很難回憶起星球大戰之前的時代
那時的世界是另一幅景象
那時候沒有手機和個人電腦
互聯網的出現遙遙無期
就連家庭電視遊戲
還有一大段路要走
- 太空競賽已經結束
- 對一個人來說這是一小步
美國人感到深陷於現狀
那時候處於通貨膨脹...
石油價格上漲...
國民對他們的英雄和領導人冷嘲熱諷
我不是騙子
在我們國家 水門(醜聞)撕開了我們
此外我們還在打越南戰爭...
前所未有地在分裂國家
那是我們歷史中可怕的十年
充斥著風暴和暴力
在大銀幕上 好萊塢的看法同樣驚心
1970年代的早期電影
gritty且常為悲觀...
反映了美國的社會與政治劇變
老式英雄已逝...
打破一切規則的頑固反英雄
統治著銀幕
在60年代末期
the Warners the Zanucks...
那些首先建立製片廠的人...
都退休了 他們把製片廠賣給了公司
有飲料公司還有所有其他行業的
他們根本不知道如何經營製片廠
他們知道的是
銷售部門說人們想看這個...
你就去拍那個
他們開始銷售電影...
研究人口統計資料之類的東西
他們意識到年輕人
拍給年輕人看的電影有市場...
因為年輕人群占市場的更大部分
持續數十年的製片制度瓦解了
好萊塢的主管們
急切地想接觸年輕觀眾...
到電影學校
來找下一代的電影製作人
- 開拍
- 在這種變革的氣氛中...
富有天賦的年輕導演
比如Francis Ford Coppola...
Brian De Palma...
Martin Scorsese...
和Steven Spielberg...
把更多的個人感性帶上了銀幕
那是個困惑的年代
很多電影製作人要做...
平時做不到的方案
我在正中間被找上了
George是北加州來的不羈少年...
一個獨立電影製作者
他總是因為...
自己與好萊塢關係甚少而自豪
出生於加利福尼亞州Modesto...
George Lucas讀著冒險故事...
看著電視連續劇長大
上大學的時候
他製作電影的夢想才浮出水面
1963年 他離開Modesto...
去參加南加州大學(USC)的電影班
我當時在USC教書
George上了一門討論課
我們討論了他電影製作的早期嘗試
我告訴你 從一開始...
George就有獨一無二的視角
George能在常規外思考...
你可以從他的學生電影
THX-1138中看出來
THX-1138 4EB
This is Authority.
You will stop where you are.
他拍了一部20分鐘的電影
本應是五分鐘
You're going for
the emergency switch.
但是他得到了大量認可
打開了教授們的眼睛...
孩子可以做出打破常規...
超越限制的東西
Lucas的專業技術和故事想像力...
贏得了大家的喝彩
他對神化和哲學的興趣
gave his work an added dimension.
George's style was fantastic.
Incredible.
不管他拍什麼...
都比其他作品看上去更個人
從USC畢業後...
Lucas與朋友Francis Ford Coppola合夥...
Coppola在1969年於三藩市
創建了美國西洋鏡公司...
一家獨立電影公司
我並不打算變得成功
但是我感到...
有能力控制自己的作品...
而不被人篡改
1971年 Lucas導演了THX-1138...
基於他學生電影的影院長片
當華納兄弟的主管們
觀看了成品後...
他們要求Coppola歸還$300,000...
the studio had advanced
to develop THX and other projects.
初出茅廬的公司imploded
Lucas得去其他地方找工作
他決定自己包攬大局...
並開了自己的公司
盧卡斯電影有限公司
它旗下的第一個項目...
Lucas選擇了『美國風情畫』...
an affectionate look at teenage cruising
in the early 1 960s.
- I'm a ready teddy.
- Well, get bent, turkey.
由環球製片廠製片...
此電影寬鬆地基於...
他在Modesto作為汽車狂熱者的個人經歷
我原是極端實驗主義且強硬...
然後接受了Francis給我的挑戰
''我賭你不會拍一部傻乎乎的喜劇''
一部溫馨虛幻的喜劇
我說 ''我去試試''
電影只拍攝了28天
成本低於100萬美元
合作製片人是也是USC的校友 Gary Kurtz
『美國風情畫』的後期製作將近尾聲...
我們在三藩市Northpoint電影院
組織了一場放映
我們感覺到觀眾的反應很積極
但是來自環球製片廠的Ned Tanen十分惱火
他說 ''你眼下不應該把它放給觀眾看''
我們完全目瞪口呆
他們不理解我的第一部電影
完成後還來干涉它
我的第二部電影也是如此
公司實體進來...
對它胡搞了一番
剪掉了5分鐘
在發表『美國風情畫』之前...
George Lucas的想像已指向星空
在此期間 他一直在說...
他想拍一部類似于『飛俠哥頓』的
1930年代的太空歌劇
他正經地著手工作
人們說 ''Of all things to pick,
why in the world would you do that?''
I said, ''It's fun to make films
for young people.
It's a chance to
make an impression on them.
I wanna do this.''
With his galactic fairy tale...
Lucas hoped to reinvent
a classic genre.
Among his influences...
were the writings of scholar
and educatorJoseph Campbell...
in which he explored the origins
of myth and world religions.
When Lucas was writing
the script of Star Wars...
he was heavily interested
in Joseph Campbell.
WhatJoseph Campbell
was interested in...
was to see the connections between
the myths of different cultures...
to try to find out
what were the threads...
that tied all these very
disparate cultures together.
I did research to try
to distill everything...
down into motifs
that would be universal.
I attribute most of the success
to the psychological underpinnings...
which had been around
for thousands of years...
and the people still react the same way
to the stories as they always have.
George is nothing
if not a good reporter.
And when he sets out
to do his work...
he starts reporting from
the best sources he can gather.
He brought Campbell
into the process...
of looking at his work
on Star Wars...
and saying, ''Is this right?
Am I getting it down?
Is this the right emphasis?
Is this the right character?''
Joseph Campbell said to me the best
student he ever had was George Lucas.
Like such epics as The Odyssey...
Beowulf...
and The Legend of King Arthur...
Star Wars drew from
a shared pool of mythic archetypes.
You have the youth who's on the
adventure that you can identify with.
You have the swashbuckler.
And you have the damsel.
She may not have the reactions
that are conventional...
however she is in distress.
And you have the wise old man,
who you go and you find him.
And you have
the funnier characters.
I mean, it really adheres
strictly to that form.
It's the traditional,
ritualistic coming-of-age story.
When I went into the mythological
side of what I wanted to do...
that's a key factor with heroes.
By the summer of 1 973...
George Lucas had created a treatment
that he felt was ready to shop around.
Whether anyone would be interested,
that was another story.
The most successful science fiction film
up to that point was 2001 .
Successful then was that
it made about $2 4 million.
Most hit science fiction films
would make about $ 1 6 million...
which was the Planet of the Apes films,
and that sort of thing.
But most science fiction films
would make under $ 1 0 million.
There's no reason to think
that it would do any different.
Star Wars was more
space fantasy than science fiction...
but its galactic setting
made it a tough sell in 1 973.
When I was pitching the film,
all I had was a 1 4-page story treatment.
It was very vague.
Said it was kind of a 1 930s...
action adventure,
Saturday afternoon serial...
based on the kind of Flash Gordon,
Buck Rogers kind of comic book future.
And that's about all
they knew about it.
In the '70s, science fiction
seemed to be...
all about apocalyptic societies
and death and destruction.
Not very inspiring.
We were fighting an uphill battle
with a science fiction project.
George Lucas brought Star Wars
to Universal and United Artists.
Both studios passed
on the project.
But the ambitious young filmmaker
was secretly relieved.
The last thing he wanted was to hand
his dream project to the wrong people.
He didn't care
for the studio system.
He used it because there was no other
way of doing what he needed to do.
Undaunted, Lucas presented
Star Wars to Alan Ladd,Jr....
the new head of creative affairs
at 20th Century Fox.
Ladd, a former producer, was able to
recognize potential in the filmmaker...
if not necessarily the film.
We had a meeting,
and George said...
''I've been thinking about
this thing called Star Wars. ''
And he told me about it.
I said, ''That sounds terrific.''
The technology part of the whole
thing was completely over my head.
But I just believed in him
and his genius.
I sort of recognized
from American Graffiti...
that he really was a genius,
so I just flew with it.
He understood what talent was.
He respected talent
and he was able to say...
''I think this guy's talented.
I think we're gonna invest in him. ''
So, Alan Ladd,Jr. invested in me.
He did not invest in the movie.
And it paid off.
In 1 973, Ladd's investment
in George Lucas provedjustified.
American Graffiti was finally
released to rave reviews...
and became the third-highest
grossing picture of the year.
It went on to earn more than
$ 1 00 million worldwide.
American Graffiti showed
a very human center and a huge heart...
that George has always had.
I think that surprised
a lot of people.
With a preliminary deal
for Star Wars in place...
Lucas began writing
his screenplay in 1 97 4.
It proved more ambitious
than he had first imagined.
The filmmaker was able to
distill his idea down to its essence--
an epic battle between
a heroic Rebel Alliance...
and an evil Galactic Empire.
The chief villain, Darth Vader,
was there practically from the start.
But it took time to come up with
Star Wars's three main heroes--
a plucky young princess
named Leia Organa...
the fearless Corellian smuggler
known as Han Solo...
and most important,
an idealistic farm boy...
whose original name
was Luke Starkiller.
Over the course ofhis adventure...
Luke trains to become
a Jedi knight...
deriving his power from a mystical
energy known as ''the Force. ''
But along the way, the script
went through radical changes.
At one point, Luke was
a 60-year-old general...
and Han Solo
had green skin and gills.
Even the concept of the Force
had yet to be fully realized.
Instead, there was
the Kaiburr Crystal...
a sort of galactic Holy Grail.
The concept of the Force was
an important one in the story.
The difficulty is...
trying to create
a religious-spiritual concept...
that works in a very simple way
without heavy exposition...
or without it seeming
to pull down the story.
It got to be a very fat script,
about 200 pages.
And the story
had gotten away from me.
So, the only way I could
cope with it was to say...
''I'll take the first third-- the first
act-- and I'll make that into a movie.''
But I'd written all this other stuff.
I'd spent a year writing this story.
I said, ''I'm not gonna throw away
two thirds of my year...
and say,
'This is all I can afford at this point.
This is the only money I'm gonna get
is to do this one movie.'''
I put it on the shelf.I said, ''By hook
or by crook, I will finish this movie. ''
But Star Wars
wouldn't be cheap.
To get the Fox board of directors
to approve the necessary budget...
Lucas needed
something dramatic.
He hired Ralph McQuarrie, a conceptual
design artist who had worked for Boeing.
I'd seen some ofhis paintings.
I thought he was brilliant.
I said, ''I want you to do some
paintings of these scenes I've done...
so that the studio can get a picture
of what I'm talking about.''
When I turned in the script, I had
about five or six drawings to say...
''This is what it's gonna look like. ''
He had a concept
for a big spectacular visual...
and it didn't come across
in the script.
So I tried to give it scale...
juxtaposing the tiny little figures...
with the great,
spectacular backgrounds.
George would say, ''Don't worry
about how we're going to do it.
Wejust want an impression of what the
scenes would look like on the screen. ''
McQuarrie's artwork won over
the Fox board of directors...
who soon approved a budget
ofjust over $8 million.
With only the first part
ofhis Star Wars saga being made...
Lucas also needed to think
about the future.
But his prior dealings with major
studios had taught him to be cautious.
When I made the deal
for Star Wars...
originally I made the deal before
American Graffiiti had even come out.
'Cause Alan Ladd had seen American
Graffiiti and said, ''I'll make a deal.''
But he made a very--
you're gonna make X number
of dollars and this kind of thing.
It was like a one-page memo.
When it came up to doing the contract
for the film, about a year later...
I knew that what I really had to do
was to protect the unwritten part--
the other two parts of the script.
All of a sudden,
Graffiti comes out...
and it's a big huge, smash success.
So his agent came back
and said, ''Hey, look.
This guy has made
this huge successful movie.
Don't you think we should get more than
a couple hundred thousand dollars...
for writing, directing
and producing a movie?''
I said, ''Yeah. I think
he should get more. ''
I was very careful to say, ''I don't want
more money. I don't want more points.
I don't want anything financial.
But I do want the right
to make these sequels.''
I was working on the assumption
every filmmaker works on...
which is the film
will be a disaster...
and that it won't be promoted
and it'll just die a horrible death.
And it'll be very hard to get
these next two movies made.
George said, ''I'd like
a big slice of the merchandising. ''
Up until that time, merchandising
had been relatively unknown.
When I took over the licensing,
I simply said...
''I'm gonna be able to make T-shirts.
I'm gonna be able to make posters...
and I'm gonna be able to sell this
movie, even though the studio won't. ''
So, I managed to get control of pretty
much everything that was left over...
that the studio
didn't really care about.
George was enormously farsighted,
and the studio wasn't...
because they didn't know
that the world was changing.
George did know the world was changing.
He changed it.
With his Star Wars contract
completed...
George Lucas
now needed a rebel force...
up to the challenge
of production.
In the summer of 1 975...
he founded the visual effects company
Industrial Light & Magic.
There was no special effects
companies in those days...
and the studios'special effects
department had been disbanded.
Part of that was because
of the expense...
and part of it was
that the American taste...
the culture had gone toward
very realistic-looking films.
We approached the visual effects
as a grand experiment, saying...
''Can we do this with a lot of people
who work on architectural models...
and in commercials and have never made
feature films before?''
We were kind oflike
a weird kind of fraternity...
of robotic photography nuts
or something like that.
I mean, this was a big movie for Fox.
We were doing commercials.
We all dreamed
about doing a feature...
and this was like
the dream come true.
So, Star Wars came along
atjust the perfect time for us.
We moved into a big empty
warehouse in Van Nuys...
right near the Van Nuys Airport
and basically started from scratch.
I mean, it was empty. In the early days,
you used to park your car inside.
There was no camera equipment,
no rooms to speak of.
Supervising at ILM
was John Dykstra...
an effects cameraman who had worked
under Douglas Trumbull...
on films like Silent Running.
I was essentially to be responsible for
doing the visual effects for the film.
We took the concept of motion control,
which is essentially an old concept...
ofbeing able to duplicate camera motion
through more than one pass...
so that you can generate
multiple elements of film...
and we made it production-savvy
by tying it into a computer...
which was, at that point,
custom-built microprocessors.
There were no PCs.
You didn't go buy a PC.
We built them from scratch.
At the same time the camera system
was being built...
another team began constructing
model spaceships.
I was one of the early hires.
They had a small art department.
There were some concept models made
out of cardboard and model kit pieces.
There were some storyboards
and some concept illustrations...
thatJoeJohnston had done.
There were some paintings
that Ralph McQuarrie had done.
Everything came
either from my sketches...
or Ralph's paintings and drawings...
and any input
that George might have.
There wasn't a lot of
outside influences on Star Wars.
George wanted it to look like
you could actually see the rivets...
so you could see the logic
ofhow it was made.
I was originally hired
to work on the Death Star...
the 40 foot by--
What was it? 40-by-80 feet or
40-by-60 feet or something like that.
Nobody wanted thejob, because you had
to spend a lot of time on your knees.
Everybody sort of cross-trained
and worked in different techniques.
That was different
than the Hollywood system...
that had very strict union rules.
But there was no way this work
could be done that way...
or no way that the Hollywood unions
could understand what we were doing.
With preproduction
gaining momentum...
Lucas next began the process
of casting his galactic opus.
He shared the audition stage
with his friend, Brian De Palma...
who was seeking actors
for the Stephen King shocker Carrie.
We were both making these movies
and casting at the same time...
so we decided to combine
our efforts.
I've made movies with very young people
that have no track record...
so I have to discover them.
Pick them and then test them
and go through them and have readings.
It takes a long time. I spent probably
six or seven months casting Star Wars.
That's a long process to sit
in a little room and interview people.
And I interviewed
thousands of people.
In casting the male leads,
Luke Starkiller and Han Solo...
Lucas looked for
individual screen presence...
as well as chemistry
between performers.
Action.
It checks out again.
There's no mistake.
- You can't find Organa Major?
- I found it. It's just not there.
I found it.
It's just not there.
What's left of it
is contaminated.
That's it there.
Look at those radiation readouts.
It's impossible.
-I've never seen anything like it.
-The Empire must have gotten here first.
The planet has been
completely blown away.
For the pivotal role of Luke...
Lucas needed an actor who could
project both intelligence and integrity.
She's part of the royal family.
They won't get anything out of her.
She knows the power of mind control.
She's part of the royal family.
They won't get any information from her.
She knows the art of mind control.
Twenty-four-year-old Mark Hamill was
a familiar face on television.
A newcomer to films, his wholesome,
easygoing manner fit the part perfectly.
I can remember a line
from the screen test...
which I don't think
ever will leave me.
Luke says, ''But we can't turn back.
Fear is their greatest defense.
I doubt the security is any greater
than it was on Aquilae or Sullust...
and what there is is most likely
directed towards a large-scale assault.''
Fear is their greatest defense.
I doubt the security is much greater
than on Aquilae or Sullust...
and what there is is most likely
directed towards a large-scale assault.
I read that line and I thought,
''Who talks like this?''
So I just did it sincerely.
How many more systems
must get blown away...
before you have no place to hide
and are forced to fight?
Don't you realize what's going on?
Kid, you take the glory
and the good intentions.
I'll take the reward.
The role of Han Solo
needed someone older...
with a more cynical edge.
What's that little droid carrying
that's so blasted important?
What's the little droid carrying
that's so important?
Harrison Ford had worked
with Lucas on American Graffiti.
But because the director
initially only wanted new faces...
he was not allowed to audition.
Do I have to sit up
to get in on the right?
Instead, he was brought in
to feed lines to the other actors.
I was given sides and asked if
I would help read the other actors.
It became my task to explain to the
other actors who were coming along...
just what it was that these sides...
were meant to be about.
They're gonna follow us.
They'll destroy your hidden bases.
- They'll destroy the whole system.
- I know.
They'll bring the Death Star too.
Lucas may have been reluctant
to use Ford at first...
but the actor won him over by
giving Han a mix of mercenary swagger...
and world-weariness.
Well, what was so clear was what the
idea was of the character relationships.
Mark was the callow youth,
I was the smart-ass...
and we each had
a clear section of turfto explore.
The planet's totally blown away.
It would've taken 1 ,000 ships with more
firepower than I've ever seen to do it.
If the Empire had a new weapon
that could do this, I'd know about it.
I'd have heard something.
Well, you know about it now.
The enemy's on the move.
We haven't much time.
- I brought you here. Now what?
- We've got to find the rebels.
- What we're carrying belongs to them.
- Their bases are very well hidden, son.
All the power of the Empire
can't find 'em.
Do you know where they are?
No. Not anymore.
I'm not gonna take you on
an impossible chase across the galaxy.
Virtually every young actress
in Hollywood...
tried out for the part
of Princess Leia.
Although the character
was the same age as Luke...
as a leader of the rebellion
Leia needed to project...
a confidence beyond her years.
The plans and specifications
to a battle station...
with enough firepower
to destroy an entire system.
Our only hope in destroying it
is to find its weakness...
which we will determine
from the data I stored in R2.
Now, our only hope
in destroying it...
is to find its weakness...
which we'll do from the data
I stored in R2.
Okay? Now, we've captured the plans
in a raid on the imperial shipyards.
But we fell under attack before
I could get the data to safety...
so I hid it in R2
and sent him off.
When R2 has been safely delivered
to my forces, you get your reward.
You have my guarantee.
What's the little droid carrying
that's so blasted important?
The plans and specifications...
to a battle station
with enough firepower...
to destroy an entire system.
One actress in particular...
seemed tailor-made
to play a princess.
As the daughter of actress Debbie
Reynolds and singer Eddie Fisher...
Carrie Fisher was the product
of Hollywood royalty.
She had no trouble conveying the
self-assurance needed for Leia Organa.
I met with Brian De Palma
and George...
and Brian did all the talking...
because George didn't talk then.
There were incredible actresses my age
being considered for this role...
so I didn't think I would get it.
But our only hope is to destroy it
before it destroys us.
Hiding is useless now.
With the Death Star, they'll continue
to go on destroying systems...
until they've found us.
We have no alternative
but to process the information...
and use it while there's still time.
I got it with the proviso
that I went to a fat farm...
and that I lose 1 0 pounds.
I think they were hoping it was gonna
come out five here and five here.
My character was someone
who was feisty and all of that...
but I felt myself
to be a bit of that too...
so it would have been unlikely that
I would be cast as a shrinking violet.
He cast us to type, in a way.
Lucas's decision to hire unknowns...
went against the advice ofhis friend
Francis Ford Coppola...
who had cast The Godfather
with stage and screen stars.
20th Century Fox
was also concerned...
about Lucas's choice of actors.
They came and said, ''These are the three
unknown people I want to go with. ''
I figured we'd gone down this far
in the road, he knows what he's doing.
I'd be lying if I said
''Oh, my God, Harrison's perfect...
Carrie is perfect,
and Mark is fantastic. ''
No, I was very nervous
about the cast.
For the important role of
aged Jedi master Obi-Wan Kenobi...
Lucas recognized that
he needed an established star.
Sir Alec Guinness was
a veteran of over 40 films...
and had won an Oscar in 1 958...
for his performance in
The Bridge on the River Kwai.
The knighted actor had
the pedigree and the persona.
The Alec Guinness role...
required a certain stability
and gravitas as a character...
which meant we needed a very strong
character actor to play that part.
Signing Guinness was a major coup.
But more casting
would be done in London...
where Star Wars
would be principally produced.
Unlike Lucas's home base
of Northern California...
London provided access to the kind of
massive soundstages...
needed for Star Wars's
ambitious sets.
The location also gave Lucas access
to Britain's top production talents.
The character of Darth Vader demanded
someone of commanding physical stature.
To fill Vader's boots...
Lucas cast champion bodybuilder
David Prowse...
whose resume included roles
like Frankenstein's creature...
in Hammer's
popular horror movies.
As Vader's evil accomplice
Governor Tarkin...
another Hammer alumnus was cast--
63-year-old Peter Cushing.
Best known as the methodical
Professor Van Helsing in Dracula...
Cushing was the perfect choice...
to portray the Death Star's
icy chief administrator.
For the part of Chewbacca, Han Solo's
towering Wookiee copilot...
Lucas and Kurtz had to look
outside normal casting channels.
But at seven feet, three inches tall...
it was no stretch for Peter Mayhew...
who had been working as an orderly
at a Yorkshire hospital.
I sat down
on one of the sofas...
waiting for George.
Door opened...
and George walked in
with Gary behind him.
So naturally, what did I do?
I'm raised in England.
Soon as someone comes in
through the door, I stand up.
George goes--
Virtually turned to Gary and said...
''I think we've found him.''
Finding the right performers to portray
robots was even more of a challenge.
Production designers had constructed
an assortment of robots and androids...
to populate the Star Wars universe.
But it would take living,
breathing actors...
to give personality
to the two main droids...
C-3PO...
and R2-D2.
To operate R2...
Lucas needed a performer small in
stature, but with a big imagination.
Enter 3-foot-5-inch
stage comedian Kenny Baker.
They couldn't find anyone
that would fit inside this robot...
to make it move.
They couldn't use kids
'cause it was quite a heavy machine.
It weighed about 80 pounds.
I'd had a lot of experience
inside costumes...
and inside cats and dogs
and goodness knows what else.
So when I got into the robot,
he said, ''Look happy. ''
So I'd go--
Inside, nobody could
see my expressions, obviously.
But you have to do something
to get the feel of the thing.
Actor Anthony Daniels...
not only had the slender build
needed for C-3PO...
but training as a mime artist.
He'd been seeing people
every five minutes.
I was there for a while and thinking,
''Well, nearly time to go, I guess.''
And then, kind of over
George's shoulder, I saw a painting...
and the most extraordinary
thing happened.
Itjust struck me, because I kind of
looked at this face...
and the face looked back at me, and we
had this extraordinary eye contact.
He's looking out of the picture
and seemed to be saying...
''Come. Come. Be with me.''
The vulnerability in his face...
made me want to help him.
Isn't that weird?
He just looks utterly vulnerable.
That painting completely changed
my attitude to the whole project.
Years later I was able to go
to Ralph McQuarrie and say...
''You realize this is all your fault.''
In March 1 976,
with casting completed...
George Lucas and company
arrived in North Africa.
It was a strange caravan of British
and American filmmakers...
working in a French-speaking nation
on a script few people believed in.
The overriding thing for me
at that stage was...
the amount of work that we had to do,
of stuff there was to achieve...
and we had grave doubts
about getting it done in time.
But the trial by fire
had yet to begin.
It was now up to Lucas
to make his movie.
Just one day into filming...
the Sahara was pelted with its
first major rainfall in 50 years.
We were going out there
to shoot on the salt flat.
I came out in the morning and the rain
was going horizontally down the street.
I thought, ''My God--''
I called a rest day on the crew,
told them to go back to bed...
because there was no way
we were gonna shoot on that.
The first two weeks of shooting,
we'd run into a lot of weather problems.
The sets had blown down,
I didn't get everything shot.
It was a disaster. At that point
I was pretty depressed, saying...
''I've got myself in way over my head.
I don't know what I'm gonna do.''
You must do what you feel
is right, of course.
With temperatures topping
1 00 degrees by midmorning...
Tunisia was anything
but fun in the sun.
Baking for hours
in heavy costume...
even the film's stunt coordinator,
Peter Diamond...
found the conditions
physically exhausting.
I was the only stuntperson
on the picture in Tunisia.
I became a Tusken Raider,
or a Sandperson.
I'm not a sun merchant.
I don't like the sun. I just burn.
So I just died
with the heat of it.
I couldn't stand it anymore,
it was so hot.
There were so many problems.
Itjust was not a good location.
We seem to be made to suffer.
It's our lot in life.
C-3PO was finally...
put together
for the very first time...
the day before
we started shooting.
R2-D2 didn't really
function that well.
He could run along
in the three-legged position...
but he couldn't turn his head
at the same time.
There were wires everywhere.
The head was on a track
ofball bearings.
I used to grab whatever I could and turn
it physically that way and that way.
Not very far.
If I went too far the wires
would go around my neck.
Then they'd say, ''Cut.!
Right, break for lunch. ''
And everybody'djust
walk away and leave me.
Then they'd remember me eventually.
That happened many times.
It was bad enough putting
on the costume for the first time...
and within two paces the left leg
had shattered down...
onto the plastic of the left foot...
and was gently
but forcibly and persistently...
knifing it...
into the soft part of my foot.
So we took it off,and I limped
to the set with one foot.
It was then I began to panic
about the days to come.
As the actors and crew began to grumble
about the adverse conditions...
it was Sir Alec Guinness who served
as a role model of professionalism.
It was, for me, fascinating
to watch Alec Guinness.
He was always prepared,
always professional...
always very kind to the other actors.
He had a very clear head
about how to serve the story.
He was the person who sort of
brought it some legitimacy.
I asked him
why he wanted to do it.
He loved the idea
of playing a mentor or a wizard...
in a morality play...
where good and evil
are so clearly defined.
Action!
- How long have you had these droids?
- Three or four seasons.
They're up for sale if you want them.
Let me see your identification.
You don't need to see
his identification.
I don't need to see
your identification.
These aren't the droids
you're looking for.
we're looking for.
He can go about his business.
You can go about your business.
Move along.
Lucas, meanwhile...
was up to his neck
in malfunctioning props...
electronic breakdowns...
and other production woes.
Star Wars was already
struggling to stay on schedule.
The only silver lining
was that after Tunisia...
the production would be moving to
a more controlled environment--
Elstree Studios outside London.
The stages at Elstree were among
the largest in the world...
and the sets, now finished
after months of construction...
werejust as impressive.
For the first time,
the entire Star Wars cast was together.
That was almost like
a whole separate movie.
It was like getting
a whole, fresh start.
And it was all new, really.
We were all
very different ages.
I was 1 9, Harrison was 33.
He was sort of
the big man on campus.
Meeting him,you sort of felt,
''Well, he'll be a movie star. ''
Costumes, makeup,
robots and aliens...
were all ready to go.
I put that mask on
and Chewie transformed me.
I transformed.
The attitude was different.
The walk was different.
Chewie turned on.
Do the scenes, come back,
take the mask off...
Peter was back.
Action.
That old man's mad.
You said it, Chewie.
Boy, where did you
dig up that old fossil?
- Ben is a great man.
- Great at getting us into trouble.
I didn't hear you give any ideas.
Cut.
But working
at Elstree Studios...
didn't mean the production
was free from problems...
or strict British union regulations.
At 5:30 we had to stop...
unless we were
in the middle of a shot.
I could ask the crew
for an extra 1 5 minutes...
but they always voted me down.
Not to put down the British crew, but
there was an attitude of''What's this?''
It didn't help that most
of the crew thought Star Wars...
was just a children's film.
At times even the actors were
hard-pressed to take the work seriously.
Didn't think it was gonna be any good.
At least I didn't.
I thought, ''This is a bit strange.''
I can remember
this lighting man--
He said, ''What is all this about?
It's a load of rubbish. ''
And we all thought the same at
the time-- ''Yeah, it's a bit strange.''
Action!
It was a princess with her hair
in weird buns on the side...
and a giant in a monkey suit
or something.
I mean,
it was very, very weird.
No more adventures!
I'm not getting involved!
Don't you call me a mindless philosopher
you overweight glob of grease!
Bang!
I'm going to regret this.
It was tough dialogue to say.
So I got, ''Governor Tarkin, I thought
I recognized your foul stench. ''
Which, I don't know about you,
but I'm always talking like that.
Governor Tarkin.
I should have expected to find you
holding Vader's leash.
I recognized your foul stench
when I was brought on board.
Charming to the last.
We used to say, ''You can type
this stuff, but you can't say it.''
George didn't really like
being in London...
I suppose,
is the best way to say it.
He doesn't like
being away from home.
He's not the most
gregarious person in the world.
He had some clashes
with the cameraman.
Gil Taylor was a very old-school
cameraman-- very crotchety.
George, coming out of
low-budget filmmaking...
was used to doing
a lot of things himself.
So George would say things like,
''Well, put a light here. ''
And Gil took offense
at that kind of thing.
He says, ''That's not yourjob, son. ''
''You tell me what
you want to see, and I'll do it...
the way I think is best
to create what you want to see.''
It was a clash
of style of working.
Slate 3 27, take four.
We're coming up
on Alderaan.
I did feel something.
I could almost see the remote.
That's good.
You've taken your first step
into a larger world.
Lucas also became frustrated...
that the costumes, sets
and other production elements...
weren't living up
to his vision for Star Wars.
The compromises required
due to the film's budget...
plagued him
on an almost daily basis.
What was disappointing
would be the cantina sequence.
It was really
imaginatively described...
and then you go in there...
and it looks like
The Nutcracker Suite.
There's a frog guy
and a mouse girl...
and a giant cricket at the bar.
It was just really disappointing.
But George says, ''Don't worry.
We're gonna fix all of this. ''
We didn't see anything
of what ended up on the screen.
So when they blew my planet up...
I was looking at a guy going like this
against a board with a circle on it.
I mean, it was funny.
Proceed with the operation.
You may fire when ready.
What?
Dantooine is too remote
to make an effective demonstration.
We will deal with your rebel friends
soon enough.
Bang!
And you call yourselves humans.
George never talked.
We felt he wanted us
to hit our marks...
and magically
accommodate our dialogue.
He lost his voice at one point.
We didn't know that for days.
And we wanted to get him
a little board that said...
''Faster and more intense.''
That was his main direction.
Hejust wanted us
to speed through it.
George is notorious
for saying, after a take...
''Do it again.
Faster, more intensity. ''
He certainly said to me, ''Terrific,
Tony. Can you do it again, faster?''
But I didn't get
''more intensity.''
I didn't think 3PO with more intensity
would be bearable. Do you?
I said all systems have been alerted
to your presence, sir.
The main entrance seems
to be the only way in or out.
We all had to fill in
a lot of the blanks.
It was more a matter of, if we did
something he didn't like he'd tell us...
rather than telling us what to do.
I think George likes people.
I think George
is a warmhearted person.
But, yeah, he's a little impatient
with the process of acting...
of finding something,
you know.
He thinks it's there.
''It's right there.
I wrote it down.'' You know?
''Do that.'' You know? And sometimes you
can't just ''do that'' and make it work.
He's really focused on what he's
trying to do and get everything right.
Is the smoke right?
Did the squibs go off right?
And we were just
taunting him mercilessly.
Carrie and Mark have
wicked sense ofhumors.
Carrie was very young...
and Mark was very young...
so they were
the junior division...
and they were always
lurking about on set.
So it kept us in stitches.
I got one outfit
for the first movie...
and as George taught me...
there is no underwear in space.
Instead of that,
there is gaffer tape.
So I was taped down.
And I used to say, we should just
make up a contest on the call sheet...
as to who's gonna rip it off.
But we didn't do that.
We were all goofing around
and trying to make George crack...
'cause he looked like
he was ready to burst into tears.
You'd try and cheer him up.
Go.
- Okay, cut.
- Cut it.
- And?
Carrie and Mark bumped in too early.
The mike was in frame.
The mike was in picture.
Go back to first positions.
The sound department
has to pay up.
That, to him, was really
inappropriate humor at the time...
because I'm sure he's in the zone
and seeing what he wants to do...
and we're just actors
trying to stave off boredom...
because we've been in
the trash compactor all morning.
Ready? And action!
- What happened?
- I don't know!
It just disappeared!
I got a really bad feeling
about this.
But it is amazing what you can do
when you have a vision, an ambition...
and when you can bend
other people's will to your desire.
The thing that kept it focused
towards the ambitions...
was George's vision
and his passion for the idea.
Perhaps the most memorable
stunt in Star Wars...
was actually performed
by Mark Hamill and Carrie Fisher--
the nick-of-time escape
of Luke and Leia...
across a yawning chasm
in the Death Star.
Mark Hamill wanted to do
as much as he could himself.
I had times when I had to keep him back
because he was too enthusiastic.
He could've got hurt.
Princess Leia and Luke Skywalker
had to swing over this void.
We couldn't afford doubles, so I said,
''I can teach them. It'll be safe. ''
My buddy and I, we put the harnesses on,
we put the wires on.
Everyone down below.
Remember, we are about 20 meters up...
looking down on them.
And as we swung across
there was a terrible tear.
My buddy said to me,
''Peter, your harness has snapped.''
Mark said, ''I'm not going in that.
It's too dangerous. ''
This is where I discovered
you had to be a good liar.
I said, ''There's nothing wrong with the
harness. I split my pants as I landed. ''
He said, ''Oh, I thought
that was the harness.''
I said, ''I wouldn't let you
do this if it was dangerous.''
Action!
They did it in one take,
and that's how we got it.
For luck.
That was really early on
in the shoot...
when I was still
worried about my weight.
I thought we were gonna miss
and I'd hit the wall...
and they will say, ''Still too tubby.
Let's bring in Jodie Foster.''
Another of
Peter Diamond's tasks...
was choreographing
the dramatic lightsaber battle...
between Darth Vader
and Obi-Wan Kenobi.
You can't win, Darth.
If my blade should find its mark,
you will cease to exist.
But I warn you,
if you strike me down...
I shall become more powerful
than you can possibly imagine.
George wanted a broadsword
type of fight...
with a touch ofJapanese behind it.
But instead of becoming
samurai moves with one hand...
I kept it with two hands...
so all the moves were two hands,
completely like that.
The first swords
were bits of wood...
with front-projection material
wrapped around them.
Now, the hardest thing for me
on the first fights--
Darth Vader was a very heavy man...
Obi-Wan Kenobi was
a gentleman, right...
who had done some fencing
in the theater.
I had to teach them,
if that was a sword...
to stop before they touched,
'cause the blades were breaking.
We broke so many blades.
They just kept snapping.
- Cut.
- Cut it!
Across the Atlantic, Fox's head
of production, Alan Ladd,Jr....
continued to offer Lucas his main...
if not his only,
support from the studio.
There was a lot of problems,yes.
Every board meeting I attended,
the subject was always Star Wars.
''The costs are rising.
It's this, it's that.
Look, we've read drafts of scripts...
that make no sense to us
in any way, shape or form. ''
It was rather unpleasant.
The things that stick in my mind
that made me laugh were, like...
memos worried about whether or not
the Wookiee should have pants.
They're looking at this thing
and saying...
''Couldn't he have some lederhosen?''
And I thought,
''Isn't this great?
You know, of all the things
to worry about.
The Wookiee has no pants.''
I think we were
two weeks over schedule.
At that point, the board of directors
at Fox started to panic...
and tell Alan Ladd,Jr. that he had to
shut that film down regardless.
So he came to me and said...
''Look, you've gotta finish
in the next week...
because I've got another board meeting,
and I can't say we're still shooting.''
I kept phoning their production
department saying, ''This is insane.
If we put on a second crew, it costs us
more than going an extra week.''
They said, ''It doesn't matter.
The studio's opinion...
is that the day deadline is more
important than the money you spend.''
The final scenes were filmed
at breakneck speed...
with Lucas
frantically bicycling...
from one soundstage to another.
I think George suffered a lot more
than I was aware of at the time.
But I was very focused
on what I was doing...
'cause this was a very busy movie,
just nonstop dawn to dusk.
We did go over at the end...
and we split into three units
right at the end.
Gary directed the second unit...
and I had the distinction of directing
the third unit of Star Wars.
My shots were things like close-up
of R2-D2's third foot going down.
Nothing too dramatic.
But that's how we finished it.
Come on.
Okay, cut. Time up. Cut.
I hope that old man got the tractor beam
down, or this is gonna be a short trip.
Hit it!
Fox originally slated Star Wars
for a Christmas release in 1 976.
Schmuck.
463, take one.
But the diffiicult shoot had put
the film severely behind schedule.
Action.
- Didn't we just leave this party?
- Give us a growl.
- What kept you?
- We ran into some old friends.
- Is the ship all right?
- Seems okay, if we can get to it.
I just hope the old man got
the tractor beam out of commission.
- Look.
- Now's our chance. Go!
With barely six months to go...
there was almost no chance
of delivering the project on time.
Okay, cut.
I hadjust finished shooting the movie,
and I was exhausted, basically...
but I had to go right from the shooting
into the finishing without a break.
Already anxious
about meeting his deadline...
Lucas was shocked when he saw the first
assembly ofhis edited film that spring.
Sir, the groiters are losing power!
All right. I'll get it.
The first cut of Star Wars
was an unmitigated disaster.
- How's that?
- Yes, that's much better.
I'd started to see things cut together.
I wasn't happy with it.
I'd come in on weekends,
and I'd recut the film on my own.
Cut.
And I tried to get the editor
to cut it my way...
and he didn't really want to,
and so I had to let the editor go.
So I had no editor.
I was behind schedule.
I had to race to finish the movie.
1 77, take two.
Lucas realized his only hope
was to start from scratch.
And I am C-3PO,
human-cyborg relations.
And this is
my counterpart, R2-D2.
- Oh, hello.
- Okay, cut.
To recut the movie, he hired
Paul Hirsch and Richard Chew...
and for several months he was able
to borrow his wife, Marcia...
who was editing New York, New York
with Martin Scorsese.
Slate 250, take seven.
Action.
You must do what you feel
is right, of course.
Right now
I don't feel too good.
On Star Wars,
the trio's first task...
was to give the film an energy
and pace that was sorely lacking.
Cut.
It was cut in a very traditional manner
ofjust playing things out in masters...
and then going
into the coverage...
and let the actors'rhythms
dictate the cuts...
rather than having the cuts...
kind of drive the rhythm of the scenes.
21 1 , take three.
Guide track.
Action!
So consequently,
there wasn't any excitement...
in the footage the way
that it had been put together.
Cut.
Richard and I would leapfrog.
If he was on reel one,
I would grab reel two.
Whoever finished that would
grab reel three and so forth.
We used shots up until
the very last frame.
- Cut.
- Can I take another one?
Very often, the very next frame would be
the flash of the camera stop.
For instance, there's a shot
of one of the Sandpeople...
who knocks Luke down, and then
he holds his weapon up over his head.
He did it once. We rocked it back and
forth so he did it a number of times.
The only things that are there
is what's presentable...
and everything
behind the scenes is a mess.
With no chance
ofbeing ready by Christmas...
a new release date
was set for summer, 1 977.
Some doubted that the movie
would ever reach theaters.
But as bad as things
had been with the editing...
the situation at ILM
was even worse.
The company was trying to create effects
that had never been done before.
They knew what they
wanted to accomplish...
but they had yet to create
anything usable for the film.
They had spent half their budget...
and ultimately I had about four shots,
none of which I would accept.
They were just not good.
That was a low point.
I had no special effects. I didn't know
if we were gonna get the ships to work.
So it was a pretty desperate time.
And we'd spent half the budget
building the motion-control cameras...
and setting the shop up.
It was a disaster to say the least.
The factory has to be built...
before the first can of peas
can be sent to the supermarket.
And I think it was a year or more...
without any film coming out,
without one shot being finished.
'Cause they were building
optical printers and cameras.
We were building models.
I know that George was
disappointed in the work...
and I'm disappointed
that he was disappointed.
But there's a certain subjectivity
to some of that stuff.
I wish he'd been happier,
but I also think that ultimately...
the work did thejob.
When word of the postproduction problems
reached the Fox board of directors...
they decided they'd had enough of
George Lucas and ''that science movie. ''
I just sat in one
executive committee meeting...
where they're hauling me
over the coals.
I just said,
''It's the greatest picture ever made.''
That ended the conversation.
They were afraid to say,
''Well,you're stupid and you're wrong...
and we want you out of this building
by 5:00 this afternoon. ''
There were some tense moments there.
With the dismal
early cut of the film...
ILM in chaos and growing pressure
from the studio...
Lucas was facing almost
unbearable battles on a daily basis.
After an especially
tense trip to ILM...
Lucas felt sharp chest pains.
Fearing a heart attack, the director
checked into a Marin County hospital.
He was diagnosed with
hypertension and exhaustion...
and was warned
to reduce his stress level.
At that point, I really felt...
I'd gotten myself into a real mess and
didn't know whether I was gonna get out.
Lucas doubled his efforts
to save Star Wars.
The situation at ILM
required drastic measures.
To get the film's crucial
special effects back on track...
Lucas had no choice
but to step in personally.
We put a production department in
at the special effects company.
I went there twice a week.
There was a certain amount
of resentment at first...
because they felt...
that they were being challenged a bit
on how they had set it up.
We felt that there was a certain
quasi-hippie mentality...
that some of them had
about the schedule.
Ultimately, I guess
we were known as a country club.
I think it looked to those guys
that there needed to be...
a really strong
production force in there...
that was going to meet
some sort of quota.
With hundreds of shots
left to be completed...
ILM would have to do a year's worth
of work in just six months.
But Lucas and Kurtz were determined
to turn the situation around.
Gary was a gearhead,
so he could understand our problems.
And George is a storyteller...
and so we have to serve his needs...
because he's the one
that's telling the story.
But we had to build these incredible
contraptions in order to do it.
George was our general.
We're his soldiers.
And we're all
fighting this single battle...
to get this film out.
We were on the front lines...
and that gave us also
kind of a feeling of being special...
and fighting this great battle
to get this thing done, whatever it is.
Luke, pull up.!
To help inspire
the effects team at ILM...
Lucas had spliced together aerial
dogfights from old war movies.
That would be like the first animatic,
which you do in the computer now...
and we matched frame to frame and
the action on that as close as we could.
It was hugely helpful.
- I got him.!
- Great, kid! Don't get cocky.
To describe that abstract world
of a battle is impossible.
Storyboards don't do it, as far as the
pacing, the rhythms that he needed.
- Thanks, Wedge.
- That was great.
As fall turned to winter, Star Wars
finally started to take shape.
That's it! We did it!
We did it!
Working from
the raw production tracks...
sound designer Ben Burtt would add
a critical new layer to the film.
Burtt had spent a year
building a catalog of sounds...
for things that didn't exist
in our galaxy.
George introduced the idea of what
he called an ''organic sound track. ''
George thought that Chewbacca
might be made up...
from recordings of dogs
or maybe even bears.
In addition, I recorded some lions
and tigers and even some walruses.
I would begin
editing them together...
and making little phrases
out of the noises.
I would take the recordings
and edit the best pieces.
You know, the bear might make
a sound that sounded angry.
Or they might make a sound
that was cute.
Or a sound like a sentence--
a ''wah, wah'' kind of a sound.
You said it, Chewie.
The voice of R2 turned out to be
the most difficult problem to solve...
in the sound design
of the first movie...
because R2 had to act
alongside of the other actors.
And the script only said...
that R2 made a sound,
or maybe R2 beeped.
I had a small
electronic synthesizer...
and I did some patches with it
and made up some electronic sounds.
But that didn't sound alive.
At one point we talked
about R2's personality...
and we felt he was developing
kind of as a toddler.
So I did a lot
ofbaby recordings...
and eventually we found that
in the discussion of R2's voice...
we were making
the sounds ourselves.
A few experiments led to
the combination of using my voice...
doing baby talk--
beeps and boops--
with the electronic synthesizer.
So R2 is sort of 50% machine
and 50% organic...
coming out of
the performance of a person.
The breathing for Vader was recorded
by putting a little tiny microphone...
down inside
a regulator on a scuba tank.
I breathed through the mask itself,
and it breathed in and out...
and out of that came the various
paces of Vader breathing.
And that sound worked out
pretty successfully.
Finding the right voice for Darth Vader
was another challenge.
And action!
Lucas never intended to use the on-set
vocal performance of David Prowse.
Start tearing this ship apart, piece
by piece, until you find those tapes!
Find the passengers in this vessel!
I want them alive!
I can still hear
David Prowse's accent...
in the Darth Vader mask, muffled,
'cause he would do the real dialogue...
in trying to curse
Carrie Fisher or something.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I'm a member of the Imperial Senate
on a diplomatic mission--
You are part of the Rebel Alliance
and a traitor. Take her away!
It was hilarious and terrifying
at the same time...
'cause we didn't know
what Darth sounded like.
That was the first time we heard him.
We were like, ''Is that it?
Is he gonna be some Scottish guy,
or what is this?''
Prowse's voice would later be replaced
with a more menacing performance...
provided by classically trained
stage and film actorJames Earl Jones.
George had hired David Prowse...
but he said he wanted
a so-called ''darker'' voice.
Not in terms of ethnic,
but in terms of timbre.
The rumor is that he thought
of Orson Welles...
and then probably thought that Orson
might be too recognizable.
So what he ends up is picking
a voice that was born in Mississippi...
raised in Michigan, and was a stutterer.
And that happened
to be my voice.
I want to know what happened
to the plans they sent you.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
I'm a member of the Imperial Senate
on a diplomatic mission to Alderaan.
You are part of
the Rebel Alliance and a traitor.
Take her away!
C-3PO's voice struck us all as
''We've got to do something about that.''
Thirty-four, take three.
We seem to be made to suffer.
It's our lot in life.
It was mentioned
a number of times...
that C-3PO might sound
like a used car salesman.
Not the English butler type.
Oh, I'm sorry, sir.
I must have fallen over.
I just came up with this voice
of an over-the-top British butler.
British because that would
be my natural mode of thinking.
A butler because
that was his role in life.
Nervous because that
was his feeling in life.
And it came as, ''C-3PO,
human-cyborg relations.''
This is my counterpart,
R2-D2.
Hello.
A few people
were brought in to record...
and an attempt was made
to see how 3PO would be...
with different kinds of voices.
I believe 30 actors coming,
and some really quite impressive names.
Stan Freberg and a few others
were auditioned.
Apparently one of them
was a major cartoon actor...
a man of literally a thousand voices,
who eventually said...
''You know something, George, Tony's
voice is pretty good for the character.
Why don't you
just use his voice?''
And eventually the discussion
just quieted down...
and it was an
excellent performance.
It synchronized
with his body motions.
It was a total character
which he created.
His track was left in the movie.
- Hey. We don't serve their kind here.
- What?
Your droids-- they'll have to wait
outside. We don't want them here.
Wait out by the speeder.
We don't want any trouble.
I heartily agree with you, sir.
Cut.
428, take seven.
Action.
Here we go.
Cut in the sublight engines.
At long last,
the editing, sound...
and visual effects
were taking shape.
But a private screening of the film
for Lucas's closest friends...
didn't do much
to bolster his confidence.
It was an early stage, you know,
sort of a second or third cut.
I had a couple of my friends
come up to see it.
Brian De Palma was in town.
Steven came.
Some other friends
came to see it.
The human characters
and the sets were there...
but, of course, all the spectacular--
you know, the Death Star fight...
and the battle inside the trench...
and all that was just...
not even there to be seen.
So, the reaction was not
a good one. I loved the movie.
I was one of the only people
in the audience that liked the movie.
All my friends were very honest:
''I don't get it. What are you doing?''
That was basically
the tenor of the whole thing.
On the other hand,
the studio and Laddie...
and his little group
saw the film.
They loved it. It was the first time
I've actually shown a film...
and one of the executives
even cried at the screening.
It was very emotional for him.
I sat my family round
the kitchen table in my house...
and I said, ''The most extraordinary
day of my life...
has just taken place,
and I want you to remember this day.
Because this is what I never dreamed--
or maybe I dreamed--
but I never thought I would have
a day's experience...
like the day I've had today
in seeing this film.''
I couldn't even believe it.
At that point I was used to studio
chiefs saying, ''This is terrible.
You shouldn't show this to
an audience. Embarrassing.''
So, it was very rewarding to show it to
people, even though it was in bad shape.
It didn't help that one critical
element in Star Wars was still missing--
There's no lock.
the musical score.
- That oughta hold them for a while.
- Quick. We've got to get across.
-Find the controls to extend the bridge.
-I think I just blasted it.
They're coming through!
I remember bugging George.
''When can we hear the score?''
Fortunately, Lucas was able
to recruit...
one of the industry's most accomplished
composers,John Williams.
Williams had recently won an Oscar
for Steven Spielberg's Jaws...
and his resume included countless film
and television scores...
including music for the original
Lost in Space television series.
I do remember George
talking about the fact...
that what we were going to see
in the film...
represents worlds
that we hadn't seen...
but that the music should give us
some kind of an emotional anchor.
We heard a romantic melody
for Princess Leia.
We heard bellicose music
for the battle scenes.
And some very heavy
declamatory thing for Darth Vader.
In March, 1 977...
John Williams led
the London Symphony Orchestra...
in the performance
of the Star Wars soundtrack.
Recorded over 1 2 days, it was
a sweeping symphonic masterpiece...
one of the few things to actually
exceed Lucas's expectations.